Hello friends, I am Prerna Arora Singh
again present among you
from Jaipur, Rajasthan and today is the fourth day of our quiz competition, it is the
third day and today again
I am present among you with a new question.
We have already announced the names of the winners of the last two days in our 10 o'clock
show Bluntly Speaking and I
want to thank the people of India who are
enthusiastically participating with us in
this program and a lot of your
answers are coming and we are very
happy that many of you are able to hear the correct answers,
it means that we are on the right
track and now
our pace is gradually increasing.
Today again I have brought a new question for you
and without wasting time I will
first flash that question for you on the screen.
So friends, today's first question is
that you are in a minor accident and cannot
drive. Your 16 year old son can drive a
car. You will, what will you do at a point? Ask
your son to drive or call the ambulance. See, you
try to drive some how and we argue with you.  The
pedestrian
friends, the question is that
you were driving on the road
and your car had a minor
accident and your 16 year old son was with you. You
cannot drive yourself,
your 16 year old son is
with you and you are expected to
behave at that time. Do you have to
go to the hospital or go back home?
So what will you do? You will
ask your 16 year old son to
drive. Point A is that you will
call an ambulance. Point C is that you will
drive yourself, even if you are
injured, you will still drive.
Or will
you
argue and fight with the people who have gathered around there? So friends, this is the
question. Choose which answer you think is correct
and participate with us in this
quiz competition.
This question is live for the next two hours. You can
go to our website and choose the correct answer,
fill in your information and it is
possible that you will be one of those three.  Be included among the lucky winners
whose names will be announced tonight. Those who have given the
correct answer, their names will be
announced tonight at 10 pm in Bluntly Speaking. So friends, let me
repeat this question once again, what is the
question? The question is that you are in a minor
accident and cannot drive. Your 16-year-old
son can drive a car. You will ask
your son to drive or call the ambulance. You
try to drive some distance and argue with the
pedestrian.
You have had a minor accident or a road
accident and you will
not be able to drive now, but
your 16-year-old son is with you. So,
what will be your choice at that time? There are
four possible answers, out of
which answer will you choose?
You have to answer that. So, the first answer
to this question is that you will ask your 16-year-old
son, who knows how to drive, to drive and take you.
You will call the ambulance. You will
wait for the ambulance. You will somehow
drive the car yourself, even in pain.  Or
you will start fighting with the passersby standing nearby,
you will
argue with them, so friends, this
is the question and it will remain on the screen for you for the
next two hours. You can participate in it
and join our competition by choosing the correct answer.
You may be among the three lucky winners
whose names will be announced tonight at 10 o'clock on our
program Bluntly Speaking, which airs
online live on TV. You may be selected for that.
Your name may be announced in that program.
As of now, the names of our 30 winners have been announced.
Friends, every day the
names of 15 winners are announced. For every question, the
names of three winners are announced.
Throughout the day, we ask you five questions.
As you may have already known, I will
repeat that if any new viewers
join us and new viewers come to know about it, then
we ask you five questions every day,
every two hours. Right now, the first
question is flashing on the screen for you at 9 o'clock.
You have time for these two hours.
To answer this question, you can
log in to our website and join India Ag OG.
You
can answer this question by logging in to
our Drive Save Drive Smart
Drive Save page or you
can type India Against Ro Crush and you will get it, you
can go there and answer it too, so
friends join us
and answer it and the next question comes at 11 am,
then after that the third question is given to you
at 1 pm, the fourth question is brought to you at
3:00 pm by my
friends and at 5:00 pm
we will release the question of the day,
you have time till 7 pm to answer it for the next two hours
and after that we
announce the names of three winners for each
question, out of those who have given the correct answer to each question,
we will select any three, if more than three
people have given the correct answer, which is our
experience of two days that the
number of people who have given the answer is a little more and the
number of people who have given the correct answer is also more, then
we will then draw lots from them through lottery, through
online lottery, through software
Then we announce the names of the winners. Out of all the
people who gave correct answers,
three will be winners for each question. There will be
15 winners in the whole day and 30 winners.
Friends, by giving their answers and
participating in this competition, they have got their prizes.
Their names have been announced
and
we have also published their names on the website and our RPF everywhere.
So you can also be one of those lucky winners.
So come and join and give correct answers.
You can answer all the five questions. It is
not that if you answer once,
you can answer all the five questions and you can get a chance to win the prize. So
what are you waiting for,
friends. Come, now I will have a little 'Issue of the Day'
which I talk to you every day,
discuss one thing at a time,
we talk on one topic. So friends, what
I will talk about today is collective participation. We will
talk about the role of our
guests who will come today, they will come from voluntary organizations
and you must have seen.  Just last Sunday,
in Mann Ki Baat, the Honorable Prime Minister
appealed to all of us, the people of the country, and all the institutions to collectively participate in the field of road safety
and what we can do to stay safe on the roads.
He
appealed to all of us to come forward
and participate. All the institutions of the country are related
institutions like police, transport, the
responsible department for road construction, NE,
PWD, DA, Municipal Corporation, roads are also built at the Panchayat level,
and the medical hospitals, and the
organizations themselves, media, education
department, and you yourself, NYKS,
Scout Guide, NCC, that is, we and an
individual person, a normal person who does not belong to a particular caste,
but he
uses the road, he uses the road
whether as a pedestrian, or riding a
bicycle, or riding a motorcycle, or driving a camel
cart, or driving a horse cart, or
driving a tractor trolley, etc. He
uses the road for some reason or the other.
Friends, the
untimely deaths that are happening on our roads are
God's will.  No, God has
told you that I have given you intelligence, I have
developed your intellect, you are
humans, you can think and understand. The
difference between us as compared to other animals is that
our intellect is developed, we
can think and understand. We can learn from the incidents that have happened so that
we do not repeat them,
we can find ways to protect ourselves from them. God has given this intellectual capacity
to humans, then how can we leave the
deaths on the road to God's mercy?
Friends, when it comes to Corona,
which is an unknown virus which is
not even visible to us, it is a small virus
and we cannot even see it, it is an invisible
virus, when we can fight it, we
can win it, if we all decide, if we all
together decide that we have to defeat it, then
today India's name is shining in the world.
Friends, the whole world is
looking towards us.
We have developed medicines, vaccines to fight Corona
in a very short time. The whole year has not even passed,
we have not reached March, we are only
in January and we have spent eight months.
We have also developed a vaccine in 2018. We have
almost conquered the disease. The
disease is not spreading; we have reduced it.
Gradually, people are recovering. They are understanding it. Every village, every
home, every
person knows how to protect themselves from Corona.
This is the only effort we can make. When we can
protect ourselves from Corona, then
we do not have to fight any virus.
Friends, we do not have to invent a vaccine for that.
We do not need to look towards anyone else that
some pharmaceutical company will make a vaccine for us.
Friends, you and I are responsible for road accidents.
Who is responsible for road accidents? You
and I. So, come, today we will discuss collective participation.
Some guests will also join me throughout the time. They will
tell you about various topics like
how together we can stop the deaths on the roads
and how we can
build the future of our India. And
I am very sure that yesterday also we had
guests, two guests came, one from
engineering, urban planner and one from
enforcement, all from Delhi.  Both of them were
from Gurgaon, one from Delhi, but both of them are
very positive. We absolutely
believe that we can win this battle and
although the global
target given by the United Nations and the world to
all the countries is to
reduce deaths by 50% by 2030,
but we are very confident and we are very confident that
now we are being talked about
and the kind of leadership we have and the kind
of public support we are getting,
we cooperated in fighting Corona, we unitedly,
if we maintain the same, then we do
not need to go till 2030, we
can easily cross this figure before even five years
because it is in our hands,
friends, we do not have to wait for anyone for this,
rather India can set an example in the world.
Now friends, with a very
sad heart, I want to tell you this that as of
today, the condition of India is due to the
deaths in road accidents and the
injuries to the limbs of the injured and the
loss of money, the economic loss
and because of that, the other
social  Challenges and problems arise,
friends, in that, India is in a very bad
condition, which means we should be ashamed
that we have made the roads of our country
so red. Is there no
value of a human being on the roads in our country? Is there no value
of his life? The value of life is due to
Corona and not due to road accidents. So,
I am starting this question among you today
and we will go and take answers on this,
we will also talk to our guests who will come
and today we will
discuss collective participation the whole day, we will talk about the role of NGOs, the
role of organizations, you
and I talk about the government, but
what are you and I doing for the
125 crore population of this country who
use the roads, what are the 125 crore people who
use the roads doing themselves, what
step are they taking themselves so that
they ensure their participation in the field of road safety,
today this
will be the discussion the whole day friends and this is the
first question on this, in this context, this question
which has been asked to you first today, is your
participation that suppose if we are walking on the road
and someone is with you  If an accident occurs
and you have a 16-year-old son who knows how to
drive, and you are
now unable to drive due to the injuries you sustained in the accident, then
you have four possible scenarios.
Which option you choose will
determine the kind of responsibility you are
playing towards us in the field of road safety. The
first answer to the question is
that you will ask your 16-
year-old son to drive the car and take
you there. The second answer is
that you will call an ambulance. The
third answer is that you yourself may have suffered a
minor injury, but still
you will manage to drive the car somehow. The
fourth is that
you will
argue with the people who have gathered around you. So friends,
answer this. There is a question before you for two hours
and I, Prerna Arora Singh,
take your leave for now. I am leaving you with this question
and I will be back at 10 o'clock. There is
a very young youth from
our country, the organization
he is currently associated with is making a name for itself at the global level.
And in India it has become the
biggest youth organization
in the field of road safety. Its
Vice President is there, he will be among us.
We will discuss with him at 10 o'clock that
what is the responsibility of these youth, the young people who are the future of our country,
how are they ensuring their participation
in the field of road safety.
We will discuss with him on this question till then please
allow me, I will be present among you again at 10 o'clock
and you answer this question
and stay connected. Thank you, Jai
Hind and